Good afternoon, everybody. Good afternoon. This is one of those days where I just feel like I'm
too smart for my own good. So I'm just eating a lot of chocolate. We're about to be joined by
Gloria de la Cruz to talk about IPCO Pastors for Peace and what they're all about. I know there's
a lot of folks in here who are on a journey that so many of us are on of just kind of like moving
through our spirituality, looking for new spaces of community. And excuse me. And so this could be
a very relevant space for many of you. I also want to let you all know that I am... You too, Phaedra.
Um, I also want to let you all know that the tickets for my live stream performance and book
launch of What Would the Ancestors Say go on sale today. So I will be posting that. I also just
submitted my book for the copyright and for in the ISBN, etc. So that will be going up on sale. I
can't even flip and believe I did it. If you don't know, the book for What Would the Ancestors Say
has not only the text of the performance of the show, of the one woman show, but it also has a
four words written by me, as well as illustrations and an additional resources list. Um, and, uh,
so I'm really proud of this piece of work. And, um, I know that $30 is steep for a lot of folks.
I completely understand and respect that. Just know that. So, however, I am doing this completely
self-published and it's worth $30. So, you know, it's just what it is. Um, one second. Let me see
where what is. Um, so, uh, yeah, so I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm looking forward. I'm looking forward. It's kind
of difficult to look forward these days, you know, it's difficult to look forward because so much of
where we are right now in this very moment is, um, so inundated with just the reality of truth. Oh.
What's up? I was, I was about to get it. I was about to really buy the book. And if you can't afford
to $30, organize three friends, chip in $10 each and build some sort of study group, it's worth it.
I'm just saying.
I appreciate you.
I'm just saying. I'm not here to say they need, I mean, I've seen, I've seen the show. My kids saw
the show and now he calls you pop, pop. Actually. And honestly, this show is so much better. Uh,
since you saw the show, because, um, I just felt that you had said something after the show. You
were like, I thought you was going to go deeper at this one point. And I was like, now I got to go
deeper. So, so I definitely, um, when you sit down and write something, it forces you to go to like
another level also, just cause now it's like on, on the page. And, um, I also want to let y'all know
that that $30, I laid out the book as well. I had to learn InDesign, Claudia.
Listen, you out here in this struggle.
You ain't never lie because the only reason I know Pro Tools is because when I was doing music,
I have no money to pay for a studio.
You know, as, as people who come from struggle, we are most, like we multitask and we develop so
many different skills. You know, we can't fit that shit in a resume. All we have to do is like,
it doesn't fit because we're just out here doing the most. Congratulations for birthing this book.
Thank you. Um, we are here to talk about what you are birthing with IFCO. And I was just telling
folks that this is a time where I know that a lot of people are really awakening to seeing their
communities as perhaps maybe not where they are finding safety or finding, um, connectivity and
that they are more open to like stepping into other communities, not realizing that the community
you're looking for has probably already been created. It's already been built. And so, uh, I would,
I think a lot of people are going to get introduced to IFCO right about now.
I mean, thank you, first of all, thanks so much for inviting me to be in conversation with you
about IFCO. IFCO is an organization that I hold very, very dear to my heart. I mean,
it introduced me to doing solidarity work with Cuba at the age of 13, doing the care events all
across the country, getting donations, like, and I'm talking about healthcare supplies, getting
education supplies, computers to bring to Cuba to support the people of Cuba. And so,
at 13, I was doing these caravans and I went to Cuba almost every year with
this humanitarian campaign to be in solidarity with the people. So, I mean, IFCO is called really
in the interreligious foundation for community organizing. And it's important to say that it
was the first black foundation that was birthed out of, um, the reparations movement of the sixties. So,
IFCO is born, yeah, it's, it's born out of the black liberation movement and the reparations movement
of the sixties is a 56, uh, 57 year old organization that has done work in solidarity with many different
struggles across the country from farm workers to solidarity work with the political prisoners. I mean,
people have might've heard of Asada Shakur probably for the first time. And I know, you know, unfortunately
when she passed, uh, not long ago, but Asada, Sundiata, Koli, Matula Shakur, like Mumia Abu Jamal, who's still
imprisoned, like a lot of work was put in and in solidarity with, with that movement from IFCO. IFCO has
done a lot of solidarity work also with Haiti. Um, it's done a lot of solidarity work again with Venice,
uh, with, uh, Cuba, with Venezuela, with Nicaragua. So it's an international organization that has carried
out, uh, solidarity work in the United States and outside of the United States. And I just came into the
position of directing IFCO. Like, so it was like a full circle, right? I came in at 13 and a lot of
solidizing and a lot of development was poured into me. And then I went back, um, eight months ago and
now I'm in the direction of, oh, I need to understand how much I've heard about the many cats. Um, this is
Sankara. Sankara. So it's not the many, it's Sankara. And so, and it's a special name. And so I just
got to show love to Sankara. Um, so IFCO has done, you know, amazing work for many years. For a long time,
IFCO has focused a lot of its work with Cuba because it's, it, it actually holds the scholarship, um,
that were granted to the United States for U.S. citizens to go study medicine in Cuba for free.
So there have been over 200 doctors that have been trained in Cuba and have come back to the United
States without having any student debt. And they are back, you know, there are clinicians. A lot of
them are also doing work in communities developing, you know, healthcare programs. They're also doing work,
um, as principals of schools that are for folks that have been in prisons or folks that are, you know,
have had issues with the very unjust criminal justice system here. So, you know, in terms of
IFCO's work, it expands, uh, a lot across different fronts of struggle. And what we're attempting to do
now in the last eight months is to be able to return much more to the root, which was the domestic work.
Why returning to the root? Because there is obviously an attack on the working class in the United States.
I mean, there's attack around healthcare that is going to affect millions of people all across the
country, particularly in the South. And we have graduated doctors that could do a lot of work in
these communities. So we're thinking about the possibilities of having these doctors organize
medical trips to the South, um, in the spring and in the fall. We're also talking about the solidarity
with Cuba. For example, we know that over the past 60 years, there has been a blockade on Cuba that
steals from the Cuban economy $15 million a day, $15 million a day. Yeah. Two days of blockade
have been estimated to be close to $40 million. So when the United States says something like the
Cuban government is a failed government, it has to do with the fact that the United States of America
has blockaded Cuba to the extent that it doesn't allow for free education, for free healthcare to be
in service of the people. You have it in the constitution, but you cannot afford to buy medicine
or medical equipment, because there are millions of dollars that are being stolen from the economy.
And so the same thing with Venezuela that is sanctioned. And so for us, it's very important
to be able to maintain that solidarity work. And so we create brigade, faith leaders, folks from labor,
folks that are community organizers, grassroots organizers, get to go to Cuba, get to experience
Cuba, get to be in conversation with the Cuban people. Um, and, you know, again,
IFCO did that for me when I was 13. A lot of what I know, in terms of popular education,
in terms of liberation theology, in terms of community organizing comes from being in conversation
with the processes in Cuba. And so I think what IFCO has done and will continue to do is to be able to
open up the door for folks that are trying to understand more about community organizing,
trying to be in touch and in conversation with people doing work in multiple fronts of struggle,
whether it's housing, whether it is healthcare, whether it is immigration. All of these things
are rooted in one thing, which is the system, the economic system in which we live, that profits
profit over people. And so, yeah.
Yeah. So the event that's coming up, sorry, Jordy sees the UPS man.
It's so good. He's gotta like it.
Jordy's jealous because he hasn't got a on you.
It's true. So he's like, let me go divert my energy to harassing this person
from a window that can do nothing about this issue. Um, so there is the event coming up,
the people over, um, the people, sorry, the people's agenda. Yeah. Can you talk about that?
Yeah. So we, we have been organizing one day, uh, summit. So one day gatherings,
we did one in Chicago in the spring and we're doing one in New York that is coming up October
25th and it's going to be held at the historic Riverside church historic because we know the many
different voices that came and preached and work through the Riverside church, including Martin
Luther King. So we will be holding the event there. There's going to be a space to bring
folks that are doing work around immigrant rights, folks that are doing work around housing,
doing work around labor and conversation also with folks that are, that are doing international work.
So, uh, folks that are doing solidarity work with Cuba, with Venezuela, with Sudan, with Palestine,
to come together and be in conversation on what does it mean to build a people's agenda?
What would a people's agenda be that could actually counteract and could actually defeat
the agenda of the billionaire class in this country? Because it is defeatable. I mean, what we
are experiencing is fear from an administration that knows that if the people come to the realization
that there are more of us than them, that we actually have the power to be able to, um, withhold
our, our, our money, to withhold our labor, to organize our communities, if we actually realize
that, then we could very easily beat their agenda. And so we're creating a space to have those
conversations. They're going to be strategic discussions and workshops as well, workshops about,
you know, what does it mean to keep each other and our community safe? So everything from, um,
um, organizing defense committees to the different coalitions that are being developed across the
city. So it's going to be fun. There's going to be culture and this is going to be, and there's
also going to be, it's going to be fun and it's also going to be informational and hopefully very
inspiring for people. Because I think one of the biggest, one of the biggest weapons of capitalism is
making us think that we're alone. Like we're the crazy ones. And, and, and we are alone in this.
And if you go onto social media and you actually see how the algorithm plays, like it's crazy. You
have high levels of distraction. And then on one end you see a genocide. And then on the other end,
you see, you know, occupations, invasions, and you don't necessarily get to see what people are doing
about it. There are a lot of people doing a lot of things around this. Like Chicago has been invaded,
but there's a whole community that is taking over the streets that is protesting, that is actually
sending these eyes demons out of their communities. Like we need to uplift that and creating that
space is precisely what allows us to get the energy that we need to be mobilized. And so that's what, what
our hope is. People are asking, people are asking if, if you're, if you're going to do any virtual
classes? If we're going to do any virtual classes? I mean, we can, we're thinking about, so one of the
things that IFCO did a lot before was organizing training. Everything from basic one-on-one organizing,
base building training is what used to do. And we want to be able to do that. And so, you know,
whether it is doing some hybrid or doing them in, in New York where we're based or traveling across
the country, we're definitely working on, on developing that arm of the organization again,
because I think it's highly important, especially when education is being attacked so hard, you know,
it's important for us to be able to tap into history. Like today, for example,
out of all the crazy shit you hear, right? Today, I saw that the opposition leader in Venezuela got the
Nobel Prize. I, that's how I started my day. And I was like, you know what? But then I was like,
but, but if we have a concept, if we have been able to tap into history, we must be reminded that
Obama bombed seven countries. Obama bombed seven countries and got the noble peace price. Peace.
Peace, right? In addition, Henry Kissinger, let's tap into history. In 1973, this man developed the cool
that would end up, that would result in the execution, in the torturing and the exile of
hundreds of thousands of Chileans and the killing of their leader, Salvador Allende. That is not talking
about what this man did in Cambodia or in other parts of the world. And he got the peace price.
So we need to understand also that this Nobel Peace Prize is a political instrument in the moment
where Trump is out here trying to invade Venezuela because he wants his oil. And I'm not just talking
shit. There's an actual video. If you go online and Google, Google, go on Google and put Trump
up, speaks about Venezuelan oil. He says, this was in his first term. He's talking about how he could
have had that oil. We could have had that oil. Because it takes 48 hours for them to go to Venezuela
and grab that oil instead of 48 days going into
West Asia. West Asia meaning the Middle East. You know what I'm saying? They are now in a crisis
internationally when they want to recolonize the countries that they haven't been able to take
because they are either with progressive governments like Mexico or because they're under socialist
governments like Venezuela. Because ultimately, if socialism don't work, let it compete. Let it develop and
let it compete. Lift the sanctions on Venezuela. Lift the blockade on Cuba. And let's see who who does
what. They have free education, free health care. Housing is a human right. So let it compete. But don't
kill it at the crib. Don't kill it at the crib. I'm just saying. Nah, I mean, it's, it's, I spoke at a
church last, this week. This week? I spoke at a church this week. Why didn't you go? I didn't tell you this? No.
I'll send you, I'll send you the two clips.
That was a revolutionary Jesus. Call me in. I don't do it.
I spoke at the Greater Allen Church in Jamaica, Queens, in Southside Jamaica, Queens. And they were doing
a revival that they called the Truth to Power Revival. And I was like, why y'all want me to come?
Yeah. I'm like, y'all know I'm not Christian, right?
You got the spirit.
Well, that's basically what the pastor was like. He was like, it's not about, you know, basically,
it's not about being Christian. It's about liberation. And I was like, you need to get down
with IFCO. And I sent him the link. And I said, you need to follow. And I said, and I talked about this
in the talk, but I was like, and much of this came from also just like conversing with you and
being on the freedom ride with other folks who are with IFCO. The reality of, you know,
spaces of worship, not simply just being aligned for the purpose of organized religion. Like,
no, there's for the purpose of organizing people as well, right? And being spaces of sanctuary,
being spaces of education, being spaces of liberation. And so many of our churches, as we
know, in the United States specifically, have been co-opted into like prosperity, what do they call it?
Like prosperity gospel. Yeah.
Yes. Prosperity gospel. Like, you see why I got this suit? This Armani suit, this is God,
because I done prayed more than the rest of y'all, which is just like absolute nonsense. And so,
you know, when you were, when you're talking about IFCO, I think there are so many people who are
feeling kind of like conflicted in their face, because they don't feel like they have,
they don't feel like the spaces where they're practicing faith are practicing the same values
that they have of liberation. No, I agree. And I think it's important for us to acknowledge that one,
the church was a big C, right? So we're talking about denominations, we're talking about
the institution of the church has kidnapped the revolutionary Jesus. Like he is being held hostage.
Why? Because if we don't have a concept of historically, where was Jesus born? Historically,
who was he fighting against? Because he was fighting against something if he was crucified in the way in
which he was crucified, right? And he was crucified specifically because he was fighting against the
Roman Empire. So that means that Jesus was an anti-imperialist. So why are we preaching that?
Why are we preaching that is the systems and structures that have been created that are the
reason for poverty? That no one individual necessarily is completely responsible for their condition.
Why? Because if it were to be an individual issue, then there will be less poor people.
But we have a massive issue all around the world with poverty. So that means that it is being created
as a result of the capitalist system. Jesus was hanging out with all the marginalized people,
was defending women, widows, all the folks with leprosy. He was with the marginalized. And so the churches
that divorce themselves from the reality of the people are no place of faith in reality. And I think
we need to be able to understand that. When we're talking about organized religion, it has served as an
institution to colonize. Can you hear me now? Oh my, did you get a phone call? Nah. Somebody muted me.
They didn't like what I was saying. The people, I mean, not the people, the man.
I mean, I don't know. Every time. But I think, again, going back to my point, I think it's important
to understand how real, and this is coming from the person of faith. Like I am. I was about to ask
you, like, give them your credentials. I'm a Christian. I'm an ordained minister with the United
Church of Christ. And I went into church, into the faith community, because it is important to tap
into a legacy also in that space. Because right now, if we think about the religious right and what
they have done politically, we cannot divorce a space of faith from the creation of culture and
the development of politics. That is real. This whole time. Say that one more time. That we can't divorce
the church space from the creation of culture. That space creates culture. It also advances a certain
politic. Whether it is creating a safe space for people not to think about what's going on,
therefore isolating and detaching people from reality and having their faith go into an active mode,
or imposing a politic that is completely right wing, right wing, and pro capitalist, like the prosperity
gospel, which is the more you have, the more you've been blessed. And if you don't have shit is on your
own is your own issue. And so I think in many ways, you know, we have to reevaluate. It's not a matter of
us like denying ourselves the opportunity to be faithful, the opportunity to have faith. We all have
spirituality, we all have spirit, we express that differently. There's people that express that
through art. There are people who express that as educators, there are people who express it as,
you know, preachers, people express it differently. But if we give up our faith, we let them win.
If we give up our spirituality, we let them win. Spirituality is connected to our values,
it's connected to what we believe in. And so in many ways, the way that I advocate for a space,
whether it is Christian, whether it is Muslim, is that it has to be a space that allows you for
critical thinking, that develops you into an agent of social change, and that allows you to organize
collectively with people to transform conditions of oppression. If it's not that, then I don't want it.
I think it's also really important that your faith practice and spirituality creates a capability for
you to fend off the brainwashing, the manipulation that is constantly, like the psyops that is constantly
being done to make you an agent of their efforts at violence, their efforts at separation, et cetera.
Like, I think people become far more susceptible to those things when they lack a certain solidity of
self, they lack a confidence of self, and they lack community. And so like these spaces,
I know that so many of us are trying to build those spaces, you know, outside of church, but as well as
in church, because I see such a dedicated effort, Claude, at them, at like turning people into weapons,
right? Like, actually making, it's like, it's like as a, as a Star Wars-ian, as a Jedi, it's like
making people clones in their Clone War. Like, we're just gonna try, we're gonna make you dumb,
and we're gonna make you willing, we're gonna make your brain open enough to accept whatever we give you.
Look, what's happening right now, I mean, what has been happening for many decades is the stupidification
of a nation. As the what, what? Is the what? Stupidification of a nation. The stupidification
of a nation. Of a nation. That's the Bronx coming out. But it is that. It's a stupidification of a
nation, and they are utilizing all the different forms of cultural production, whether it is church,
whether it is the education system, whether it is social media, and mass communication, like, there
is the desire to kill critical thinking. Like, I sit there, and I watch these, you know, media conferences
coming out of the White House. And I, I'm like, why do, like, how do people connect? Like, how are people
watching this? And like, saying, like, yeah, that makes sense. And at the same time, given the fact
that as an organizer, and as someone that is in constant engagement with these communities and
people, I'm like, they have created an echo chamber that is so tight. And it has so much power, you know,
and it's sophisticated in terms of like, the power that it has, in terms of the media, in terms of, you
know, the politics, the money, that it makes us think that there's a lot of people that
think that way. But the reality is that you go outside, and most people are not down with this
shit. No, they're not. And so but the echo chamber is such that they're like, this is what it is. And
so I feel like in many ways, when churches, community churches, or even denominations,
because there's big denominations, there's the Catholic churches, all these churches, when they
don't step up, and speak up, and do what they need to do, they're actually, they're complicit, and
they're in service of everything that's happening, everything that's happening. And the reality is
that when people feel like they're being choked, like their lives being choked out of them with all
these attacks, they go to church, they go to find community, they go to find some sort of like, relief,
and hope. And, and what they get is a couple minutes of distraction. And then they come out
to reality, unequipped, but without to, yeah, unequipped, like we're there, you know, unequipped
to deal with it, without the critical thought without the, you know, the level of criticism that we need
to hold for, for the level of violence that our communities are, are being exposed to, and that is
being imposed on them. Like, I look at Chicago, and the many people that at some point were like,
oh, you know, that's not my business, this has to do with immigrants. Well, they went to the south
side of Chicago, they went to the project. Claudia, they were still saying, y'all leave us out of it,
I say, you know what, then I'm not gonna say shit about Chicago, if that's what y'all want.
But, but they went there, and guess what they did? They had babies sick-tied. These were black
and brown babies. These were kids who were also citizens. These were the early, the early who were
also citizens. So what we need to understand is that the ways in which Trump is working is to be
able to strengthen, to strengthen, and in many ways, develop even further mechanisms of repression.
So if we talked about mass incarceration, and we were like, we need to end mass incarceration,
he's expanding that shit. And it's not only for immigrants. It's not only for immigrants.
And it's not only by Trump, right? Like, if you look at Atlanta, they have black Democrats in power
that are 100% behind the expansion, Cop City, all of that, right? You have folks like Tyler Perry,
who are in Atlanta, who are- Why you gotta go name that dude? Because Tyler Perry has a damn Versailles
that he's building in Atlanta, and he was donating money to the cops. Listen, like, him and Van Jones,
and many other Negroes need their black cards revoked, because they are actively working against
black people every fucking day. Honestly, at this point, I don't even think that they know what
working for black people is. I feel like the concept of blackness is similar to Christianity at this
point, and where it's been so co-opted by so many people that it's like, do y'all even know what this
really is? Well, let me tell you, I think that people have understood blackness with culture,
which is cool. But it's not. But that's it. But that's an offshoot. But that's the minimum.
Blackness is- Boots on the ground is the minimum. Yeah. I mean, boots on the ground is the minimum.
Yeah. But when our folks understand blackness a lot of the time- No, I mean the dance.
Because that's what I keep seeing folks being like, this is what black people doing,
the dance with the fans. And I'm like, that ain't gon' cut it, playboys and girls.
Exactly. Exactly. I honestly do believe that when we think about blackness, we also need to come
to terms and where did it, like, the term black, the identity of black, where did it
originate? And it originated through politics. It, like, blackness, black liberation, it originated
through hundreds. Talk about it. Because we were called other things before we called ourselves
black. Yes.
Which is why when people be on this internet, like, black is a color, it's not a, I'm like,
oh my god. It's a, it's a politic. Folks should read black jacobins. Yes. Folks should really read that,
which is about the Haitian Revolution, and in which, she can't really read black jacobins,
which speaks to the Haitian Revolution, and the, their understanding, the understanding of those
who were fighting for their liberation of the black identity. Because if we're not talking about,
that's right, if we're not talking about liberation, and liberation not meaning, like,
through economic development alone, like, having no power, girl, man. Okay. Continue, continue. I'm,
I'm impressed that you were able to keep going. That's love, y'all. I love you. That's, you know,
you know, we're here, you know what I'm saying? I think it's important for us to understand, not even,
like, if we're not even talking about economic development alone, for one individual, because
people see, like, oh, Michael Jordan, he made it, Oprah made it, and we keep on, and you can see how
old I am, because I still got Michael Jordan as a reference in Oprah, but you look at all these,
all these folks that are black, that have made it, that does not constitute the liberation of black
people massively. So can you talk about the concept of making it within that context? Because I think
that is where a lot of people get lost, is that, and I can say that as myself, like, for a long time,
the concept of making it was so cordoned within, like, just the capitalism and the ability to,
um, to acquire a certain amount of wealth that, you know, and by the way, for the most part,
a lot of people, quote, unquote, make it, and then they realize, oh, this actually isn't making it.
Yeah. Um, so can you just talk about, like, how, how this idea of making it, like, what it actually is
presented as versus, and, and why it's presented that way? Because I feel like the, the idea of
black folks making it is this black excellence that undermined black revolution. I mean, we talk
about making it, we're talking about making it to something that has been created not by us or for us,
making it into an economic and political system and a social system that has been white supremacist,
that has been xenophobic, that has been patriarchal, and we have fought our way in. Now, that does not mean
that that space will change, and that could go for anything. That could go, like, we both went to
Colombia. We, we went to, like, elite universities. The fact that you go and get that education and get
that degree does not change the reality. We see it doesn't change Colombia. Yeah, it doesn't change
Colombia, but it doesn't also change the reality of the world. There might be individuals that are
produced in those spaces that try to make certain changes in given moments and spaces. That does not
change the construction of capitalism. It doesn't change the construction of patriarchy. It doesn't
change you as imperialism. And so we need to be really clear that in this society, when we say
that person made it, they made it into a system that works against us every day. And those people who
make it need to make concessions to be able to get to those spaces. Facts. Facts. I mean, I,
I had to understand that in real time. You know, like, I quote, unquote, made it. And it was like,
well, if you want to keep it, then this is where the concessions begin. Right? Because that's the
other part of it, too, is that some of your favorites might be the most outspoken, et cetera,
people, and that gets them to a certain point. But if they want to stay there, that's when you start
seeing them have to capitulate, have to shape shift, et cetera. Someone like Van Jones, I mean,
he was always a cornball. Don't even get me twisted. Like, don't even get it wrong. Like,
he was a cornball when he was an organizer as well. Nonetheless, he like gets to this point
where then he's offered $100,000 for criminal justice reform, which by the way, this criminal
justice reform tag that they put on things, I know that a lot of people want to want to believe that
that really is something that's going to do something. But anytime you see reform attached to
something, it lets you know that it's not trying to actually end it. It's just trying to shapeshift
it. So when you saw Jay-Z and Beyonce having a dinner at a criminal justice reform charity event
alongside Ivanka Trump and Jared Kushner, folks was like, but it's a criminal justice reform charity
event. I'm like, no. Let's, everybody calm down. Everybody calm down. And I think part of the
concessions, right, that these folks make in those spaces, that's one. And then the concessions that
those spaces need to make to the masses to pacify them, right? So like these reforms are concessions
that come from struggle. Like people demand, people fight, people organize, you know, people are out
there making it the point that we deserve humanity, that we deserve dignity. And so what they do is, okay,
what is the least that we could give them that doesn't crumble the structures that we need and
pacify these people enough so that we could give them these crumbs and keep them with their mouths
shut. That's Democrats. That's what it is. And so these reforms are concessions that are made by those
who have economic and political power. It doesn't shift the relationship to power. When we're talking
about liberation, we're talking about that shift where the majority of the people working class
people actually have the economic and political power to decide over our lives and livelihoods,
not have these billions, look at that, the shutdown, the government shutdown, you know,
who's still getting paid? These politicians, they still get paid, they still get paid, but federal workers
aren't getting paid. So we need to be clear that these people, these people who serve billionaires,
regardless of whether they're Democrats or Republicans, they get paid, regardless of whether
we don't or do, they have the economic power. And so what we are fighting for is not reforms,
we're fighting for liberation. And that's what we need to keep in mind. And I think in many ways,
you know, people may say, Oh, you know, mobilization, protest, whether they do, they do.
But that's not the end. No, we need to build the organizations that allow us to build the power
to fight for power. And so if all we're doing is going to protest, of course, of course, we're going
to feel like protest doesn't do anything. But if we're in an organization that's actually building
every day, day in and day out, that's organizing, that's educating, that's moving people, that is,
you know, building a certain level of power that is locally, that is regionally, that is nationally,
that is collaborating with other organizations, then we feel a little less worried about whether
marching or, you know, marching or not makes a difference or not, because we're doing making
the difference every day. And I think that's the realization that we need to get to.
So that's the thing, y'all. I know a lot of a lot of folks are not seeing it to be their
responsibility to either become part of organizations or support organizations. Like, I will tell y'all,
so like, I am not a member of organizations, because I'm just not that kind of gal. However,
I do my best to be in support of multiple organizations, as much as possible, right,
even being here with Claudia and giving platform to IFCO. Tomorrow, I'll be a part of the walk with
Proyecto Faro, which is an immigration support organization in Rockland County. There's always
organizations that are doing the work that you're thinking about at home that needs to get done.
Like, do not get it twisted. There's very rarely you coming up with like, you know what?
Ain't nobody doing it. Yes, they are. Even if it's two people. The other problem, though,
is that you have front end ass organizations that are really actually upholding the problem.
Yeah, that's right.
Right. Instead of being able to move through it. And so it's like parsing through that.
That being said, IFCO is not that girl. IFCO is that girl. So can you please just give folks
more information on how they can be a part of the summit, where they can RSVP, all the good things?
So, you know, for starters, if folks could follow IFCO underscore pastors for the number P.
And I've tagged it right here at the bottom. Amazing.
I think the website for the summit that are happening is www.peoplesagenda2025.org.
People could go onto the website and RSVP there. It's going to be a whole day of discussions,
exchanges, workshops, and building. Because that's what we need to do, building. We need to break the
isolation that is also being imposed on us. Like these rates, these abductions that are happening
in our communities are literally a way of showing force and scaring people. Like people don't want
to leave their homes. There's a reason for that. There's a reason that they're doing this. And so
we need to be able to find the courage in collective spaces and collective action. And so that's what we're
trying to do, trying to build and working towards building. And folks are more than welcome to be there.
So I am going to get back to work. And you all already know what your work is to do. And again,
you see it tagged at the bottom NYC. Go to RSVP at peoplesagenda2025.com.
.org. If they go to the .com part, they probably go to another website. I think it's .org. Yeah.
Okay. Peoplesagenda2025.org. Okay. So you're going to go to peoplesagenda2025.org. I'm
absolutely going to save this live. I got to transcend. So don't worry about it. You're
going to be able to check it back. So go to peoplesagenda2025.org and register for the one-day
summit with IPCO. It's October 25th. Some people were saying that the flyer says 9am,
but the ticket says 10am. 9am is for registrations. We're starting at 10. So folks can be there
anytime between 9 and 10. They'll be registered. They're listening to music, talking, mingling,
mingling, and we're starting off at 10. Okay. And this is happening at the Riverside
Church, y'all. So if you don't know where the Riverside Church is, it's uptown on Riverside.
It's legendary, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera. So hopefully we will see you there. Thank you so
much for y'all. All right, my love. Take care. Cuídate. I'll see you later. Bye, everyone. Bye.